The power of one person
does not amount to much.
As such, I will do all I can,
however little that may be,
to protect those who are dear to me.
Those below me will protect those below them.
We tiny humans should be
able to do that much, at least.
Geometric progression, huh?
Which means...
in order for you to protect the whole country,
you'll have to be standing
at the top of the pyramid.
I'll bet it feels awfully
good to be there, Hughes.
But I won't be able to
climb that high all by myself.
I'm sure of that much.
What are you swaggering on about?
This could be interesting.
I'll take a piece of that action.
I want to see how your naïve
idealism changes this country.
Colonel...
Colonel!
If you're tired, why don't
you go to the nap room?
Sorry. I want to gather up
all the unfinished paperwork
before we transfer to Central.
I haven't slept much lately.
You seemed to be having a dream.
Oh, it was just an insignificant old memory.
Kono omoi wo keshite shimau niwa
mada jinsei nagai desho?
Yarinokoshite'ru koto
yarinaoshite mitai kara
Yume no tsuzuki oikakete ita hazu na no ni
Magarikunetta
hosoi michi hito ni tsumazuku
Ano koro mitai ni tte modoritai wake ja nai no
Nakushite kita sora wo sagashite'ru
Wakatte kuremasu you ni
Gisei ni natta you na
kanashii kao wa yamete yo
Tsumi no saigo wa namida ja nai yo
Zutto kurushiku seotte'ku n da
Deguchi mienai kanjou meiro ni
dare wo matte'ru no?
Shiroi nooto ni tsuzutta you ni
motto sunao ni hakidashitai yo
Nani kara nogaretai n da
...genjitsu tte yatsu?
Kanaeru tame ni ikite'ru n datte
Sakebitaku naru yo Kikoete imasu ka?
Bunan ni nante yatte'rarenai kara
...kaeru basho mo nai no
Yasashisa niwa itsumo kansha shite'ru
Dakara tsuyoku naritai
(I'm on the way)
Natsukashiku naru
konna itami mo kangei jan
So, I don't remember
anything after this one kicked me.
Guardians who were only
souls, a precious sacrifice,
and him letting you live...
Uroboros tattoos, a
Philosopher's Stone transmutation circle,
and Mr. Marcoh saying
they used Stones in Ishval...
There are too many mysteries
here for just a simple experiment.
And there's no way to investigate any further,
what with the lab being a pile of rubble.
"Hmm..."
It sounds like they're talking
about something pretty thorny.
I don't want to stick my nose
into anything any more dangerous,
so I'm not listening!
Ah, you there,
is this where the Fullmetal Alchemist's room is?
Yes, this is--
If I root around in the criminal
lists at the court-martial office,
something might turn up.
I shall look into those who
were working under Dr. Marcoh
in researching the Stone.
Excuse me.
F-Fuhrer King Bradley!
Ah, keep your voice down. As you were.
Your Excellency, what are you doing here?
What, you ask?
Visiting a sick friend. Do you like melons?
Yeah, thanks.
I mean...!
I understand you've been
checking up on the senior staff members,
Major Armstrong.
Sir? Um, er, sir, how did you...
Don't underestimate my information network.
And Edward Elric...
the Philosopher's Stone?
What have you found out?
Depending on how much you've learned...
Just kidding!
You needn't be so defensive!
Huh?
I know that there is some
unrest among the ranks.
I think that something must be done about it.
Ah, that's just...
A list of those who were
researching the Philosopher's Stone.
All of these men have gone missing.
Sir?
They disappeared several days
before the 5th Laboratory collapsed.
The enemy is always a step ahead of us.
And even with my information network,
as it currently stands,
I have no handle on the enemy's size,
their objectives, or how
far they've penetrated us.
In other words, it's quite
dangerous to be poking around.
Mm-hmm.
Lt. Colonel Hughes,
Major Armstrong, Elric brothers,
I've determined you to be men that I can trust.
I will not permit you to stick your noses
any further into this matter,
nor speak of it to anyone!
Under the present circumstances,
when we can't tell friend from foe,
you cannot trust anyone!
Consider everyone in the military
to be the enemy, and act discreetly!
However...
when the time comes,
I will have much work for you to do,
so see that you are ready.
Yes, sir!
Excellency!
Where is His Excellency, the Fuhrer?!
Uh-oh, my pesky
subordinates have come after me.
I secretly slipped out of work, you see.
Well, farewell!
Ed! Huh...?
What's wrong, everyone?
Nothing, a storm just passed through.
I bought the tickets you asked me to.
The train tomorrow at noon is okay, right?
Yeah. Thank you.
My, you sure are on the go.
You haven't even completely healed.
You expect me to stay in this
disinfectant-reeking place forever?
Where are you going now? Dublith?
Yeah. I talked it over with Al,
and we're going to go see our teacher.
I sure am scared, Brother!
I'm sure she's gonna kill us!
D-Don't wimp out,
little brother! I'm scared, too!
Who is this teacher of yours?
Still quite a distance beyond Dublith.
Whereabouts?
Let's see... here.
Right in the middle of the southern area.
W-What?!
Here! Here! Just before Dublith!
The holy land of automail, Rush Valley!
I've always wanted to go there!
Take me! Take me! Take me! Take me!
Go there on your own.
But who will pay my traveling expenses?
Are you trying to mooch off of me?
Now, now, where's the harm?
It's on our way, and all.
If you insist.
Hooray!
I'll go call Grandma!
She'd make a fine wife.
Don't tell me!
Though, not as fine as my own wife!
Okay, Papa's heading out now!
Papa, are you coming home early today?
Hmm, I'm not sure. Papa has a lot of work to do.
But I'll come home as soon as I can.
--That tickles!
--You're going to be late.
Winry, you're leaving today, right?
I won't be able to come
see you off, so take care.
Mr. Hughes, thanks so much for everything.
Whenever you're in Central,
be sure to come visit us.
Consider our home as your home.
Also, give my regards to the guys, okay?
Right.
Papa, work hard!
Come home safe!
What made you suddenly
decide to go see your teacher?
There are two reasons.
Lately, we've been on a real losing streak.
Huh? You're going there because
you want to improve your fighting?
What are you, fighting fools?
No, dumbass, it's not as simple as that!
It's not just the fighting,
it's what's inside us, you might say.
Right?
Yeah. Anyhow, we feel like
if we go see our teacher,
it will help to strengthen us somehow.
I want to get even stronger.
What's the second reason?
To ask our teacher about
the Philosopher's Stone.
The truth within the truth.
We never did end up figuring out what it was.
Our teacher might know something about it.
We can't afford to be
concerned about appearances.
We have to be ready for
Teacher to kill us, and ask her...
ask her... ask her...
Our lives sure have been short, huh?
I wish I could have at least found a girlfriend.
What kind of teacher do you have...?
The Liore insurgency?
Yes, where that new
religion "Letoism" or whatever
was suckering the people.
Sounds like it's finally under control.
Between Ishval and these insurgencies,
the eastern area is
having a rough time of it, huh?
It's not just the eastern area.
There are uprisings and border
skirmishes in the north and west, too.
The bodies are piling up all over, are they?
The government might just
be overthrown before too long.
Colonel, where are you going?
I'm running over to the archive room.
Liore...
uprisings all over... The Philosopher's Stone...
ingredients are humans...
what we did in Ishval...
Hey, now, who was it that came up with this?
I have to tell the Fuhrer, quickly...
It's a pleasure to meet you, Lt. Colonel Hughes.
Or perhaps I should say, "farewell."
Cool tattoo you've got there.
You've learned too much, Lt. Colonel Hughes.
Damn!
"Damn"? That's what I was going to say.
Oh my, Lt. Colonel Hughes.
Here to call and brag
about your family some more--
Colonel, you're bleeding!
It's nothing! I need the phone!
The prefectural office...
Sorry to have bothered you.
Eh? Colonel!
Yes, Eastern Command Center.
Put me through to Colonel Roy... Mustang.
We have a rule against
connecting anyone from an outside line.
This is Lt. Colonel Hughes, in Central!
I'm calling from outside
because it's an emergency!
Your code, please.
Ah, geez, what a pain!
Uncle, Sugar, Oliver, Eight, Zero, Zero!
Code verified. Just a moment, please.
Hurry it up! The military is in trouble!
Would you mind putting
the receiver down, Lt. Colonel?
Come on, put it down.
Lieutenant Ross?
No, it isn't. Who are you?
I'm 2nd Lieutenant Maria Ross.
Have you forgotten?
No you're not.
Lieutenant Ross has a mole under her left eye!
Oh, is that right? How careless of me.
Is this better?
What is this?
It's like I'm dreaming or something.
It's awfully unfortunate for
you that your mind works so fast,
Lt. Colonel Hughes.
Hey, now, have a heart.
I have a wife and daughter
waiting for me at home. I can't go
dying here!
Nice rendering, huh?
You son of a bitch!
Call from Lt. Colonel Hughes,
in Central, on a public line.
Again? Put him through.
I'm here. If you're bragging about
your daughter, I'm not listening.
Hughes...?
Hughes... Hey, Hughes!
You humans really are such fools.
You risk your lives over
the most pointless things.
Elicia... Gracia... I'm sorry...
I promised... I'd be home... early...
Oh, this is good!
This apple pie is the best!
Mrs. Gracia is a very good cook.
I know.
The quiche she made for us
before was also awfully delicious.
I put it on the list of things
I want to eat when I get my body back.
She taught me how to make it,
so once you get your body back, Al,
I'll make it for you.
All right!
Mr. Hughes and Mrs. Gracia
were both really great people.
Colonel Hughes is a doting father, a busybody,
and annoying to be around.
He did always come by your hospital room
to give you a hard time, huh, Brother?
Seriously.
He said he was busy with work,
but he would always come to visit me.
Next time we're there,
we ought to thank him somehow.
Yeah.
Mama,
why are they burying Papa?
Elicia...
If they do that, Papa
won't be able to do his work.
Elici--
Papa said he had a lot of work to do.
No!
Don't bury him!
Papa!
Promoted two grades
for dying in the line of duty...
Brigadier General Hughes, huh?
What good does it do to have someone
who said they'd support me from below
get above me, you idiot?
Colonel...
Alchemists are nasty creatures,
aren't they, Lieutenant?
There's a part of me that
was just frantically piecing together
the theories of human transmutation in my head.
I think I can now
understand what those boys felt
when they tried to transmute their mother.
Are you all right?
Yes, I'm all right.
Oh no, it's started to rain.
No, there's no rain--
Yes, it's raining.
Y-Yes, you're right.
Let's go back. It's chilly out here.
He left, saying he was
going to the archive room.
That was the last time I saw the colonel.
Did he get into a fight with someone?
Probably.
There were traces of blood
leading from inside the
room out into the hallway.
And the next place he went was...
The colonel was hurt,
and was about to place a call,
but then he didn't call anyone, and just left.
He picked up on something
in the court-martial office,
and even though he
could have called from inside,
he deliberately went
outside to try to contact me.
The Eastern Command Center
switchboard operator
heard Hughes say "The military is in trouble!"
What was it? What was he trying to tell me?
Colonel...
I've brought Major Armstrong.
We have some suspects as to those
who murdered Lt. Colonel Hughes.
Then why aren't you out
there catching them, right now?!
We have some suspects,
but we don't know who they are.
What do you mean? Explain yourself.
I cannot.
I am a colonel, and
I'm telling you to explain it!
Are you going to disobey a superior officer?!
I cannot tell you.
All right. I'm sorry to have called you out.
You're free to go.
Yes, sir.
Come to think of it,
I forgot to mention something.
The Elric brothers were here
up until just a few days ago.
The Elric brothers?
Yes, the Elric brothers.
Did they find what they were looking for?
No. After all, it is an
item of legendary proportions.
I see. Thanks.
Not much information
to be gathered from that, is there?
Man, I tell you,
the major is far too unsuspecting.
He said "those who killed Hughes,"
which would mean there is
more than one person involved.
It could be that there are
people working as a group.
The fact that he wouldn't tell me anything,
even though as a colonel I ordered him to,
means that there is someone
above me who has forbidden him to talk.
Someone to do with the senior staff, I'll bet.
And what the Elric brothers are looking for--
which is to say, the Philosopher's Stone.
So how is an organization having
to do with the senior military staff,
connected to the
Philosopher's Stone and Lt. Colonel Hughes?
I don't know yet.
But once I transfer to Central,
I'm going to make sure
to investigate the senior staff,
and smoke out whoever killed Hughes.
It's not like you to mix
public and private affairs.
There's nothing "public" or "private" about it.
All of this, whether
taking the position of Fuhrer
or avenging Hughes,
I do of my own personal volition!
I'm going to stick it to the
senior staff. Are you coming?
After all this time, you have to ask?
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora o
nee kimi wa oboete imasu ka
Yakusoku chigiri shoka
no kaze ga tsutsumu
futari yorisotta
Muri na egao no ura
nobita kage o kakumau
Dakara kizukanu furi saisei o erabu
Table no ue no furuenai shirase machitsuzukete
kuuhaku no yoru mo kuru hazu no nai asa mo
zenbu wakatte'tan da
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora o
nee itsuka omoidasu deshou
Hatasenakatta yakusoku o idaite
futari arukidasu
Chasing the young girl Paninya,
who stole his silver watch,
Ed and the others dash through Rush Valley,
not knowing what lay in store for them.
Next time on Hagane no Renkinjutsushi:
Fullmetal Alchemist,
Episode 11: "Miracle at Rush Valley."
Were the words the boy engraved
his resolve, or something else?